# HANNA TEFERA

San Diego, CA, 92124 | **Phone**: 619-632-2485 | **Email**: <a href="mailto:hannatefera2@gmail.com">hannatefera2@gmail.com</a> | **LinkedIn**:LinkedIn.com/in/hanna-tefera Github: Github:com/HannaBella | **Portfolio**: Hannabella.GitHub.io/Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Economics and lifelong dedication to learning. Accomplished AS Degree in IT a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from UCSD Extension. Enthusiastic about developing websites and apps with a focus on responsive design and development. Effective both in collaborative and individual work and known as problem-solver and detail oriented. Experienced in working under a fast paced and stressful work environment.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Languages:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJs, Handlebars, MySQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose, Express & ReactJS.

Applications/Tools: Git, Github, Visual Studio, Heroku and Slack

#### **PROJECTS**

Cinephile Central | Repo: github.com/HannaBella/Cinephile-Central.gits | Deployed: hannabella.github.io/Cinephile-Central/

- It is an app that serves as a one-stop shop for all movie fans. With one search users can discover movie reviews from top critics and free streaming.
- Designed and built movie review feature and DOM manipulation. Consumed NY Times api to fetch movie reviews from top critics and OMDB api to get imdb id that was used to retrieve streaming sites.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Lodash, ¡Query, JSON and Utelly API

ChefMEup | Github Repo: https://github.com/HannaBella/chef-me-up.git | Deployed: https://chef-me-up.herokuapp.com

- chefMEup is an interactive app that renders possible recipes based on the users ingredients in their fridge. Sign up users can save their favorite recipes and even can share their own recipe.
- Responsible for database design, association and query. Built ingredients and recipe api.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, NodeJs, Express, and Heroku

Mheels | Github Repo: https://github.com/rgonz166/project3.git | Deployed: https://mheels.herokuapp.com

- Mheels is an app that tracks food trucks and locate vendors near to users. The app not only shows the vendor location but users can view the menu of their chosen food truck.
- Built most of the components and the general layout. Developed client side API to consume server side API.
- ReactJS, ES6, Reactstrap, JavaScript, Auth0, MongoDB, Mongoose, NodeJs, Google API, Twitter, Express and Heroku

## EXPERIENCE

Passenger Service Agent Washington Dulles Airport, Dulles, VA

 Lufthansa
 2011 – 2014

 Ethiopian Airlines
 2012 – 2015

- Acknowledge customers presence and greet customers in a professional manner.
- Prepare a daily routine plan and assign about 15 agents for their duty.
- Verify document and visa requirement, check-in passengers, and issue board pass for more than 200 passengers.
- Reschedule misconnected passengers which demand quick problem solving skills and efficiency under a fast paced and stressful work environment.

**Statistician** Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Central Statistics Agency 2008 - 2010

• Analyze data and prepare monthly and quarterly reports for 25 to 30 internal users.

### EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: UCSD Extension, San Diego, CA 2019

AS Degree in Information Technology: Northern Virginia Community College, Sterling, VA 2014 - 2016

Graduated with Summa cum laude (GPA 3.93/4)

**BA in Economics**: Alemaya University, Alemaya 2003 - 2006